Guide to the American Business Consultants, Inc. Counterattack: Research Files TAM 148
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
American Business Consultants, Inc. Counterattack: Research Files
1930-1968
TAM 148
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
44.0 linear feet (44 boxes)
American Business Consultants, Inc. was formed in 1947 by several former agents of the Federal Bureau of Investigation to investigate allegedly subversive organizations and individuals, particularly those affiliated with the Communist Party, USA. In May 1947, A.B.C. began publishing Counterattack in New York, a for-profit weekly "newsletter of facts to combat Communism." The collection is comprised of research files for individuals, organizations, events and activities which were considered to reflect communist influence, and contain clippings, ephemera, internal documents, correspondence, and investigative reports, some of which were of an undercover nature. NOTE: This collection is housed offsite and advance notice is required for use.
American Business Consultants.
Provenance
Gift of Liberty University (Lynchburg, Virginia), 1992. From 1968-1985, held by the Church League of America, an organization which also maintained records regarding allegedly subversive Communist activities and organizations.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions. NOTE: This collection is housed offsite and advance notice is required for use.
Historical/Biographical Note:
American Business Consultants, Inc. was formed in 1947 by several former agents of the Federal Bureau of Investigation. This organization established itself as a source of information regarding allegedly subversive organizations and individuals, particularly those suspected of affiliation with the Communist Party, USA. In May 1947, A.B.C. began publishing Counterattack, a weekly "newsletter of facts to combat Communism." A.B.C. was one of a number of research enterprises which amassed information regarding Communist-related organizations, but it was also an entrepreneurial enterprise which sought to turn a profit. The founders of Counterattack, including former FBI agent John G. Keenan, who became Counterattack's President, solicited subscriptions from "Security Officers, Personnel Directors, Employment managers and all sorts of people whose business requires them to know the facts about the background of organizations and/or individuals." Headquartered in New York, Counterattack's orientation was primarily, though not entirely, New York-based, reflecting the geographical concentration of the CPUSA.
Publications such as Counterattack can be viewed as products of the domestic ramifications of the Cold War era. American Business Consultants formed one segment of a larger network, which included the House Un-American Activities Committee, involved in research into allegedly Communist-related activities of individuals and organizations. Since its membership was composed of former FBI agents, not only did A.B.C. possess information obtained by this agency, but it also had access to the files of HUAC. (Burlingame, p. 87)
The connection between the two agencies was made manifest in 1950, when Counterattack published a booklet entitled Red Channels, which listed possible "subversives" in the world of radio and television. Addressing itself to radio and television company executives already embattled by recent HUAC investigations, Red Channels simply listed a series of names of persons in show business, and the number of times each person had been cited by the FBI or HUAC, without making any specific accusations against any given person.(Burlingame, p. 152) The potential of "guilt by association" involved in this technique resulted in a series of libel suits filed against Counterattack by various film and radio personalities. Although Counterattack eventually defended itself against these libel suits, settling some out of court while winning others on appeal in 1956, the financial cost of litigation proved hazardous to Counterattack. As a result, John Keenan in a 1963 memorandum affirmed a "hands-off policy" regarding Communism on the part of the publication. The organization officially disbanded in 1968.
Scope and Content Note
The Counterattack collection consists of research files organized into eighteen series, arranged numerically (by series number, and within each series, by file number). The research files contain clippings by and/or about the subjects (individual or corporate) researched; ephemera, internal documents, correspondence; and investigative reports and correspondence, some of which was of an undercover nature. The research files are organized into series, each of which is assigned a number. The lowest series number in our holdings is series 9, and the highest series number is 99. NOTE, however, that (a) we only have 19 series, (b) that there are many gaps in the series numbering, (c) and that the gaps in series numbers may represent series numbers not assigned, OR series which are missing from the collection. The richest series are 11 (CPUSA), 12 (CP Fronts), 13 (CP influenced Unions, described below), 14 (Individuals), 50 (Miscellaneous, notably containing several rich files on the Illinois Communist Party and its one-time leader, Gil Green). Descriptions for selected series follow, below. A complete list of all the series (giving series number and title, number of folders, and box numbers), directly precedes the Box & Folder List. One notable item is Index of Photographs in the Daily Worker from February 2, 1922 to December, 1942 (bulk: July, 1927-1942), compiled by Benjamin Mandel, for the Special Committee on Un-American Activities (HUAC). This document, containing entries for some 3500 photographs, is in series 11, and is also available separately and can be ordered from the Tamiment Library. NOTE: This collection is housed offsite and advance notice is required for use.
NOTE: An asterisk (*) preceding the folder title denotes a folder found to contain especially valuable documentation, usually in the form of undercover investigative reports, internal documents or correspondence of the organizations and/or individuals in question. The presence of an asterisk (*) is a positive statement about a particular folder only. The absence of an asterisk (*) in front of a folder title is not a definitive statement that these folders do not contain significant documentation and/or the types of documents described above, although of less importance.
NOTE: A plus sign (+) preceding the folder title denotes a folder found to contain materials by or about anti-communist, right-wing organizations or individuals.
NOTE: Most folders on Serials chiefly or solely contain Counterattack subscription correspondence.
NOTE: Date spans for folders in Series 9 and 10 are often approximate. Folders may contain materials from a wider date span than indicated.
Series Description
series/file: boxes: title
Series 13 (Trade Unions), contains extraordinary details about how unions coped with the attacks on their loyalties. The files on the American Communication Association and the American Radio Association describe how the Marine Division of the ACA left that Communist-influenced union, moving first to the Marine Engineers Beneficial Association before setting itself up as the ARA. In addition to convention proceedings and reports, the files contain many minutes of locals' meetings during this period for New York, New Orleans, Baltimore and several other cities. The Transport Workers Union files contain more information on the prewar period than most other files, with several testimonials by ex-members, as well as reports from "informants" during the post war period. The United Electricians, Radio and Machine Workers Union files, the largest set of files in the collection include several right-wing reports on the Communist leaders of the union. One report focusing on Minnesota includes an in-depth description of the Communist Party apparatus in that region. In addition, there are daily reports from an agent who worked at UE National Headquarters in 1952, and extensive reports from an agent documenting a machine workers strike in 1946. The files on the United Office and Professional Workers of America discuss attempts to organize workers on Wall Street, and include union financial reports that Counterattack used to trace payments to Communist front organizations There is also good information on fighting between the union and Prudential over the company's attempts to move insurance agents into other unions. The Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Workers of America files contain a very large number of daily reports by insiders, documenting a strike against Macy's, an extended dispute against management at Bloomingdale's, and an organizing drive at an A&S in Brooklyn, supplemented by a large amount of fliers and newsletters from both sides.
Series 14 (Individuals), contains files on over 200 individuals, including leading and rank and file communists, progressives, fellow travelers, and liberals, leading figures in the arts, sciences and professions, and files on the following individuals whose papers are held by the Tamiment Library: Cedric Belfrage, Leo Isaacson, Saul Mills, Michael Quill, Annette Rubinstein, and Morris Schappes.
Series 50 (Miscellaneous: Organizations, and some Individuals): One highlight of this series are four fat folders on the Communist Party in Illinois, 1948-49, including the correspondence and reports of a highly-placed informant who apparently had access to the state chairperson, Gil Green, and includes some material by Green. There are also ten folders on Communist Party USA leaders, arranged by state and or region.
Arrangement
Arranged numerically by series and file number.
Organized into eighteen topical series (see scope and content note).
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
The Cedric Belfrage Papers
American Business Consultants.; Bunche, Ralph J. (Ralph Johnson), 1904-1971; Communist Party of the United States of America (Ill.); Communist Party of the United States of America.; Counterattack (New York, N.Y.).; Green, Gil, 1906-; Keenan, John G.; Progressive Party (U.S.: 1948).; United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America.; Anti-communist movements |z United States.; Biography files.; Clippings (information artifacts).; Communism |z New York (State); Communism |z United States; Communists |z United States; Correspondence.; Documents.; Domestic intelligence |z United States; Endowments |z United States; Labor unions and communism |z United States; New York (N.Y.).; Reports.
- Series 9: Individuals, Organizations, Topics, Miscellaneous (arranged by file number)
  Scope and Contents note
  Catch-all series - mostly clips on individuals, topics, organizations
  - (pg# 1-100 ) Subversive Activities, 1950-1963 (Box 1, Folder 9-0)
  - (pg# 101-236 ) Subversive Activities, 1961-1963 (Box 1, Folder 9-0)
  - (pg# 237-349 ) Subversive Activities, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 9-0)
  - (pg# 350-430 ) Subversive Activities, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 9-0)
  - (pg# 431-480 ) Subversive Activities, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 9-0)
  - (pg# 481-507 ) Subversive Activities, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 9-0)
  - (pg# 508-532 ) Subversive Activities, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 9-0)
  - (pg# 533-570 ) Subversive Activities, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 9-0)
  - (pg# 571-647 ) Subversive Activities, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 9-0)
  - (pg# 648-741 ) Subversive Activities, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 9-0)
  - (pg# 742-839 ) Subversive Activities, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 9-0)
  - (pg# 840-934 ) Subversive Activities, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 9-0)
  - (pg# 935-1012 ) Subversive Activities, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 9-0)
  - (pg# 1013-1064 ) Subversive Activities, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 9-0)
  - Pillion Resolution HJ 447, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 9-2)
  - Literature re Communism, 1957-1962 (Box 2, Folder 9-3)
  - National Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy (SANE), 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 9-4)
  - (pg# 1-63 ) +John Birch Society, 1961-1963 (Box 2, Folder 9-5)
  - (pg# 64-150 ) +John Birch Society, undated (Box 2, Folder 9-5)
  - (pg# 151-258 ) +John Birch Society, 1965-1972 (Box 2, Folder 9-5)
  - Highlander Folk School, 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 9-6)
  - *+Minutemen, 1961-1969 (Box 2, Folder 9-7)
  - + On Target(Minutemen), 1965-1970 (Box 2, Folder 9-7A)
  - (pg# 1-104 ) NAACP (National Association for the Advancement of Colored People), 1956-1966 (Box 2, Folder 9-8)
  - (pg# 105-213 ) NAACP, 1958-1967 (Box 2, Folder 9-8)
  - (pg# 214-255 ) NAACP, 1969-1972 (Box 2, Folder 9-8)
  - +Moral Re-Armament, 1961-1963 (Box 2, Folder 9-9)
  - +Florida Minutemen, 1961-1969 (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
  - Project Alert of South Broward (Florida), 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 9-11)
  - +Young Americans for Freedom - folder contents trfrd to 45-82, section I, undated (Box 2, Folder 9-12)
  - +Young Americans for Freedom - folder contents trfrd to 45-82A, undated (Box 2, Folder 9-12A)
  - Daily Worker, 1937-1968 (Box 2, Folder 9-13)
  - Life Line (radio program), 1962-1970 (Box 2, Folder 9-14)
  - Political Affairs, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 9-15)
  - Mainstream, 1962-1965 (Box 2, Folder 9-16)
  - Missing folder, undated (Box 2, Folder 9-17)
  - (pg# 1-124 ) +Klu Klux Klan, 1961-1967 (Box 2, Folder 9-18)
  - (pg# 125-236c ) +Klu Klux Klan, 1965-1970 (Box 2, Folder 9-18)
  - National Indignation Committee, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 9-19)
  - Jack Gordon (Miami, FL), 1956-1966 (Box 2, Folder 9-20)
  - CPUSA, 1961-1971 (Box 2, Folder 9-21)
  - Congress of Racial Equality (CORE), 1961-1970 (Box 3, Folder 9-22)
  - Common Sense(Christian Education Assn), 1961-1966 (Box 3, Folder 9-23)
  - +Major General Edwin Walker, 1961-1965 (Box 3, Folder 9-24)
  - The Nation, undated (Box 3, Folder 9-26)
  - +Awake and Survive, Inc. (Tampa, FL), 1961 (Box 3, Folder 9-27)
  - *+Dr. Harold D. Jerome (Coral Gables, FL), 1962 (Box 3, Folder 9-28)
  - American Bar Assn Anti-Communist Seminar, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 9-29)
  - Americans for Democratic Action (ADA), 1961-1972 (Box 3, Folder 9-30)
  - Empty folder, undated (Box 3, Folder 9-31)
  - Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, 1962-1968 (Box 3, Folder 9-32)
  - Donald W. Branch (Miami, FL), 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 9-33)
  - +American Nazi Party, 1962-1971 (Box 3, Folder 9-34)
  - National Guardian, 1963-1966 (Box 3, Folder 9-35)
  - Science and Society, 1962-1966 (Box 3, Folder 9-36)
  - World Marxist Review, 1962-1969 (Box 3, Folder 9-37)
  - The Justice(Brandeis University), 1962 (Box 3, Folder 9-38)
  - William P. Davis (North Carolina), 1963 (Box 3, Folder 9-39)
  - Humanity Guild, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 9-40)
  - Freedomways, 1963-1970 (Box 3, Folder 9-41)
  - New World Review, 1962-1967 (Box 3, Folder 9-42)
  - National Council of Churches, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 9-43)
  - Marxist-Leninist Quarterly, 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 9-44)
  - Hammer and Steel, 1963-1968 (Box 3, Folder 9-45)
  - Vanguard, 1963-1966 (Box 3, Folder 9-46)
  - *Young Peoples' Socialist League at Florida State University, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 9-47)
  - Muslim - cult of Islam, 1963-1972 (Box 3, Folder 9-48)
  - Walter Reuther, 1965-1969 (Box 3, Folder 9-49)
  - +National States Rights Party, 1964-1971 (Box 3, Folder 9-50)
  - Student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee, 1963-1970 (Box 3, Folder 9-51)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU), 1964-1972 (Box 3, Folder 9-52)
  - National Council for Civic Responsibilities, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 9-53)
  - W.E.B. DuBois Clubs of America, 1964-1968 (Box 3, Folder 9-54)
  - Weekly Crusader(Christian Crusade), 1965 (Box 3, Folder 9-55)
  - Kilsoo K. Haan ( Korean Underground Report), 1964-1970 (Box 3, Folder 9-56)
  - Southern Christian Leadership Conference, 1962-1972 (Box 3, Folder 9-57)
  - Workers World(Workers World Party), 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 9-58)
  - The Partisan(Youth Against War & Fascism), 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 9-59)
  - * Southern Patriot, 1965-1968 (Box 3, Folder 9-60)
  - The Militant(Socialist Workers Party), 1965-1967 (Box 3, Folder 9-61)
  - Social Questions Bulletin(Methodist Federation for Social Action), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 9-62)
  - Four Lights/Peace and Freedom(Womens Intl League for Peace and Freedom), 1965 (Box 3, Folder 9-63)
  - I.F. Stone's Weekly, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 9-64)
  - International Socialist Review, undated (Box 3, Folder 9-65)
  - New America(SP-SDF), 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 9-66)
  - Progressive Labor, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 9-67)
  - The Progressive, 1963-1966 (Box 3, Folder 9-68)
  - (pg# 1-96 ) Teach-Ins and College Infiltration, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 9-69)
  - (pg# 97-168 ) Teach-Ins and College Infiltration, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 9-69)
  - (pg# 168-287 ) Teach-Ins and College Infiltration, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 9-69)
  - (pg# 288 ) Teach-Ins and College Infiltration, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 9-69)
  - Soviet Embassy, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 9-70)
  - Liberation, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 9-71)
  - Young Socialist Alliance, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 9-72)
  - Weekly People(Socialist Labor Party), 1966 (Box 3, Folder 9-73)
  - Young Socialist(Young Socialist Alliance), 1966 (Box 3, Folder 9-74)
  - Economic Notes(Labor Research Assn), 1965-1967 (Box 3, Folder 9-75)
  - New Politics, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 9-76)
  - New Times(USSR), 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 9-77)
  - International Affairs(USSR), undated (Box 3, Folder 9-78)
  - Peking Review, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 9-79)
  - Labour Monthly(Gt. Brit), undated (Box 3, Folder 9-80)
  - World Trade Union Movement, undated (Box 3, Folder 9-81)
  - Angela Davis, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 9-83a)
  - Angela Davis, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 9-83b)
  - UNESCO, undated (Box 4, Folder 9-84)
  - F.A.C.T.S. in Education, undated (Box 4, Folder 9-85)
  - China Today, undated (Box 4, Folder 9-86)
  - Missing folder, undated (Box 4, Folder 9-87)
  - Soulbook(Berkeley, CA), 1965-1968 (Box 4, Folder 9-88)
  - Insurgent(W.E.B. DuBois Clubs), 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 9-89)
  - Union Democracy in Action(Labor Democracy Workshop), 1965-1968 (Box 4, Folder 0-90)
  - Martin Luther King, 1965-1968 (Box 4, Folder 9-91)
  - Progressive Labor(empty folder), undated (Box 4, Folder 9-92)
  - Bombings, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 9-93)
  - Challenge-Desafio(Progressive Labor Party), 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 9-94)
  - Youth Against War and Fascism, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 9-95)
  - Empty - "see file 9-51", undated (Box 4, Folder 9-96)
  - Revolution(Paris), 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 9-97)
  - Spark(San Francisco, Progressive Labor Party), 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 9-98)
  - The Idler(Washington, D.C.), 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 9-99)
  - Ramparts, 1965-1968 (Box 4, Folder 9-100)
  - Progressive Worker(Vancouver, B.C.), 1965-1968 (Box 4, Folder 9-101)
  - Communist Activities in the Dominican Republic (transferred to 74-1), undated (Box 4, Folder 9-102)
  - Fact, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 9-103)
  - +Let Freedom Ring (right-wing phone network), 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 9-104)
  - Central Committee for Conscientious Objectors (CCCO), 1965 (Box 4, Folder 9-105)
  - China Pictorial, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 9-106)
  - Chinese Literature, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 9-107)
  - China Reconstructs, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 9-108)
  - Viet Report, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 9-109)
  - Western Socialist, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 9-110)
  - Soviet Life, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 9-111)
  - Streets, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 9-112)
  - Appalachian South, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 0-113)
  - The New Republic, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 9-114)
  - "Cuba, school for radicals" ( Miami Herald series), 1970 (Box 4, Folder 9-115)
  - The Spider, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 9-115a)
  - (pg# 1-82 ) Vietnam, demonstrations & protests, 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 9-116)
  - (pg# 83-172 ) Vietnam, demonstrations & protests, 1965-1971 (Box 4, Folder 9-116)
  - (pg# 173-231 ) Vietnam, demonstrations & protests, 1968-1971 (Box 4, Folder 9-116)
  - American Institute for Marxist Studies (AIMS), 1965-1970 (Box 4, Folder 9-117)
  - *Socialist Labor Party, 1965-1971 (Box 4, Folder 9-118)
  - Prometheus Book Club, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 9-119)
  - Catholic Worker, 1965-1968 (Box 4, Folder 9-120)
  - Contemporary Issues, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 9-121)
  - Moscow News, 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 9-122)
  - Horizons, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 9-123)
  - Cuba Socialista, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 9-124)
  - Marxism Today, 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 9-125)
  - World Youth, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 9-126)
  - World Student News, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 9-127)
  - Washington Observer, 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 9-128)
  - Muhammad Speaks, 1965-1971 (Box 4, Folder 9-129)
  - Teachers Committee for Peace in Vietnam, 1965-1968 (Box 4, Folder 9-130)
  - Group Research, Inc., 1962-1972 (Box 4, Folder 9-131)
  - Scan(Ontario), 1966 (Box 4, Folder 9-132)
  - Deacons for Defense and Justice, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 9-133)
  - Newsletter(Southern Student Organizing Committee), 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 9-134)
  - Daedalus, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 9-135)
  - Humanist, 1966-1968 (Box 4, Folder 9-136)
  - New York Review of Books, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 9-137)
  - Atlas, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 9-138)
  - Jewish Daily News, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 9-139)
  - Communist Viewpoint(Communist Party of Canada), 1966-1969 (Box 4, Folder 9-140)
  - Rev. Philip Berrigan, et. al., 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 9-141)
  - Peace Keeping Ways and Means Committee, Inc., 1966 (Box 4, Folder 9-142)
  - "A portrait of China", 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 9-143)
  - Jewish Currents, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 9-144)
  - Embassy of the USSR (Information Bulletins), 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 9-145)
  - +Organization to Abolish Federal Income Tax, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 9-146)
  - Guild Practitioner(National Lawyers Guild), 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 9-147)
  - Manchester Guardian, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 9-148)
  - New York Independent, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 9-149)
  - Carlos Gonzales (contents transferred to 69-10-4), undated (Box 5, Folder 9-150)
  - The Independent, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 9-151)
  - Studies on the Left, 1965-1968 (Box 5, Folder 9-152)
  - Missing folder, undated (Box 5, Folder 9-153)
  - *K. Baarslag (A), 1944-1965 (Box 5, Folder 9-154-173)
  - *K. Baarslag (A-B), 1943-1956 (Box 5, Folder 9-174-195)
  - *K. Baarslag (B), 1943-1965 (Box 5, Folder 9-196-270)
  - *K. Baarslag (B), 1953-1968 (Box 5, Folder 9-271-286)
  - *K. Baarslag (B), 1954-1964 (Box 5, Folder 9-287-297)
  - *K. Baarslag (Browder, Earl), 1942-1966 (Box 5, Folder 9-298)
  - *K. Baarslag (B), 1931-1964 (Box 5, Folder 9-299-309)
  - *K. Baarslag (C), undated (Box 5, Folder 9-310-370)
  - *K. Baarslag (C), undated (Box 5, Folder 9-371-383)
  - *K. Baarslag (C), undated (Box 5, Folder 9-384-387)
  - *K. Baarslag (C), undated (Box 5, Folder 9-388-401)
  - No folders for these numbers, undated (Box 5, Folder 9-402-684)
  - *K. Baarslag (H), undated (Box 5, Folder 9-685-690)
  - *K. Baarslag (H - J), undated (Box 5, Folder 9-691-727)
  - *K. Baarslag (K), undated (Box 5, Folder 9-728-771)
  - *K. Baarslag (K), undated (Box 5, Folder 9-772-777)
  - *Dr. Martin Luther King, 1963-1965 (Box 5, Folder 9-778(I))
  - Dr. Martin Luther King, 1963-1965 (Box 5, Folder 9-778(II))
  - *K. Baarslag (K), undated (Box 6, Folder 9-779-783)
  - *K. Baarslag (L), undated (Box 6, Folder 9-784-833)
  - *K. Baarslag (L), undated (Box 6, Folder 9-834-840)
  - *K. Baarslag (L), undated (Box 6, Folder 9-841-859)
  - *K. Baarslag (M), undated (Box 6, Folder 9-860-956)
  - *K. Baarslag (M), undated (Box 6, Folder 9-957-969)
  - K. Baarslag (Kissinger, Henry), 1972 (Box 6, Folder 9-970)
  - *K. Baarslag (M), undated (Box 6, Folder 9-971-980)
  - *K. Baarslag (M), undated (Box 6, Folder 9-981-988)
  - *K. Baarslag (M), undated (Box 6, Folder 9-989-1009)
  - *K. Baarslag (N), undated (Box 6, Folder 9-1010-1034)
  - *K. Baarslag (O), undated (Box 6, Folder 9-1035-1049)